Waco Conference of Christians and Jews records, Inclusive: 1980-1996, undated, Bulk 1980-1990
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Waco Conference of Christians and Jews records
Inclusive: 1980-1996, undated, Bulk 1980-1990
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
2701
Greater Waco Interfaith Conference
Waco Conference of Christians and Jews
2 document boxes and 1 oversized box
This collection contains speeches, photographs, and records of the humanitarian work done by the Waco Interfaith Conference (formerly known as the Waco Conference of Christians and Jews).
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Excellent.
Biography/Profile
The Waco Conference of Christians and Jews (known as The Greater Waco Interfaith Conference as of 2002 September) was first proposed in a 1980 February meeting hosted by Dr. Gary Cook, who would become the organization's first president. Mrs. Payton Kolb of the Arkansas Conference of Christians and Jews challenged those present at the meeting to organize a Conference of Christians and Jews in the Waco area. Dr. Cook took the challenge and invited the community to attend a discussion about the formation of a Waco chapter of the conference, prompting their first official meeting on 1980 March 6. Their first sponsored event was a Holocaust remembrance worship service in 1980 September at Baylor University.
Since then, the organization has sponsored and created several programs and events centered in the Waco area. The first Annual Dinner was created in 1981 as a fundraiser for the organization. The honorary chairperson is recognized at this annual dinner, and the Humanitarian and Family of the Year awards are presented. The organization also held seminars on various topics including the dangers of the Klu Klux Klan (with speech given by Leon Jaworski), the rise of Neo-Nazism, the rights of religious liberties, and institutional racism. Another prominent annual event established in 1983 was the "Tour of Understanding" which invited board members and members of the community to visit local places of worship for dialogue.
In order to reach the maximum number of people in the Waco area with their message, the organization changed its name to The Greater Waco Interfaith Conference in September 2002. This change came with the addition of new board members representing Islam, the Hindu religion, and the Baha'i Faith. The organization continues to operate.
Scope and Content
The collection is divided into two series: I. Public Events and II. Organizational Documents, which are both equivalent in scope and size. The first series contains newspaper clippings, photographs, and film negatives from various events sponsored by the organization, mostly taking place during the late 1980's. This series also contains pamphlets, programs, newsletters, invitations, and speech transcripts related to the various programs sponsored by the organization. This series is in excellent condition. The second series, organizational documents, contains minutes, bylaws, financial records, memos, recommendations, correspondences, history documents and award information. This series has documents dating from the organization's creation in 1980 to meetings and events from the early 1990's. This series is also in excellent condition.
Arrangement
Prior to current processing, the collection consisted of two document boxes each containing file folders separated by clippings, photographs, and paper documents. The folders did have titles, but the titles did not always correlate to the contents.
There are now two series: I. Public Events and II. Organizational Documents.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 2701. Acquired 1985-10-00
Related Resources
Related references
"The History." The Greater Waco Interfaith Conference. Accessed 2017 February 2.
Waco Conference of Christians and Jews, Accession #2701, Box 2, Folder 1, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.
Index Terms
Places
Waco (Tex.).
Subjects
Judaism -- Relations -- Christianity.
Genres
By-laws.; Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.); Correspondence.; Financial records.; Minutes (Records); Photographs.; Programs.; Speeches.; VHS.
- Public Events, 1981-1996; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains speech transcripts, newspaper clippings, photographs, and film negatives from various events sponsored by the organization, mostly taking place during the late 1980s. This series is in excellent condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  Photo negative; Photographic print; Video home system (VHS) tapes
  - Tour of Understanding Photos (1 of 2), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tour of Understanding Photos (2 of 2), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fourth Annual Dinner Photographs, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fourth Annual Dinner Negatives, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Poor Man's Supper, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Human Rights Banquet (1 of 2), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Human Rights Banquet (2 of 2), 1989 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Event Photos, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Event Photos (1 of 2), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Event Photos (2 of 2), 1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Program, Invitation, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Newsletter, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Saint James United Methodist Church, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Pamphlets, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Clippings (1 of 4), 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Clippings (2 of 4), 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Clippings (3 of 4), 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Clippings (4 of 4), 1981-1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Seminar Information (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Tour of Understanding, 1983-1992 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Organizational Documents, 1980-1995, undated; 2
  This series contains documents, minutes, bylaws, financial records, memos, recommendations, correspondences, history documents, and award information dating from the organization's creation in 1980 to meetings and events from the early 1990's. This series is in excellent condition.
  - Board of Directors Documents, 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Board of Directors Documents, 1988-1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Board of Directors Documents, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Board of Directors Documents, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Human Rights Committee, 1983-1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Holocaust Remembrance Committee, 1980-1995 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Annual Dinners, 1981-1995 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - History of Organization, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Jewish Immigration Activism, circa 1988 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Thank-You Notes, circa 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Financial Reports, 1988-1990 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Speeches, 1982-1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)